[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
We saw how we could change the threshold from zero to one for deciding
رأينا كيف يمكن أن نغير العتبة من صفر إلى واحد لاتخاذ قرار
what's a positive value to navigate between the optimistic classifier and
حول ما يعتبر قيمة موجبة للتنقل بين التصنيف المتفائل
the pessimistic classifier.
والتصنيف التشاؤمي.
There's an actually really intuitive visualization that does this.
وهناك بالفعل تصور بديهي حقًا يفعل ذلك.
It's called a precision-recall curve.
ويسمى منحنى الدقة والإرجاع.
Precision-recall curves are extremely useful
وتعتبر منحنيات الدقة والإرجاع مفيدة للغاية
to understanding how a classifier is performing.
لفهم كيفية أداء التصنيفات.
So in this case, you can imagine setting two points in that curve.
لذا في هذه الحالة، يمكنك أن تتخيل وضع نقطتين في هذا المنحنى.
What happens to the precision once you have,
ماذا يحدث للدقة بمجرد أن تقوم،
when the threshold is very close to one?
عندما تصبح العتبة قريبة جدًا من واحد؟
Well the precision is going to be one because we're going to get everything
حسنًا، ستكون الدقة واحد لأننا سنقوم بكل شيء بشكل صحيح
right, there's very, very few things and very sure they're going to correct.
لأن هناك أشياء قليلة جدًا وأنا متأكد جدًا من أننا سنقوم بها بشكل صحيح.
But the recall's going to be zero because you're going to say everything's bad,
ولكن ستكون الإرجاع سيكون صفرًا لأنك ستقول إن كل شيء سيء،
everything else is bad, so that's pessimistic.
كل شيء آخر سيء، لذا فإن هذا متشائم.
On the other extreme, our precision recall curve, the point on the bottom there,
ومن ناحية أخرى، لدينا منحنى الدقة والإرجاع، النقطة في الأسفل هناك،
is a point where the optimistic point where you have very high recall because
هي نقطة حيث النقطة المتفائلة حيث يكون لديك إرجاع عالٍ جدًا لأنك
you're going to find all the positive data points, but very low precision,
ستريد إيجاد كافة نقاط البيانات الإيجابية، لكن مع دقة منخفضة جدًا،
because you're going to find all sorts of other stuff and say that's still good.
لأنك ستقوم بإيجاد كل أنواع الأشياء الأخرى وتقول إنها لا تزال جيدة.
And so that happens when t is very small, close to zero.
ولذا فإن هذا يحدث عندما تكون t صغيرة جدًا، وقريبة من الصفر.
Now if you keep varying t,
الآن إذا حافظت على t متفاوتة،
you have a spectrum of tradeoffs between precision and recall.
فسيكون لديك طيف من المفاضلات بين الدقة والإرجاع.
So if you want a model that has a little bit more recall but still highly precise,
وبالتالي إذا كنت ترغب في نموذج يحتوي على إرجاع أكثر قليلًا ولكن لا يزال عالي الدقة،
maybe you set t = 0.8, but if you really want really, really high recall,
فربما تقوم بتعيين t = 0.8، لكن إذا كنت حقًا تريد إرجاع عالٍ حقًا،
but trying to improve precision a little bit, maybe set t to 0.2.
ولكن ربما في محاولة لتحسين الدقة قليلًا، فربما تقوم بتعيين t إلى 0.2.
And you can navigate that spectrum to explore the tradeoff between
ويمكنك التنقل عبر هذا الطيف لاستكشاف المفاضلة بين
precision and recall.
الدقة والإرجاع.
Now there doesn't always have to be a tradeoff, if you have a really
والآن لا يتعين دائمًا أن توجد مفاضلة، إذا كان لديك
perfect classifier, you might have a curve that looks like this.
تصنيف مثالي حقًا، فقد يكون لديك منحنى يشبه هذا.
This is kind of the world's ideal where you have perfect precision
وهذا هو نوعُ من التصنيفات المثالية في العالم حيث لديك دقة مثالية
no matter what your recall level.
بغض النظر عن مستوى الإرجاع الخاص بك.
This line basically never happens.
ولا يحدث هذا الخط ابدأ بشكل أساسي.
But that's kind of the ideal.
ولكنه مثالي نوعًا ما.
That's where you're trying to get to, is that kind of flat line at the top.
هذا هو حيث تحاول الوصول، ذلك النوع من الخط المسطح في الجزء العلوي.
So the more your algorithm is closer to the flat line at the top,
لذا فكلما كانت الخوارزمية الخاصة بك أقرب إلى الخط المسطح في الجزء العلوي،
the better it is.
وكان ذلك أفضل.
And so precision-recall curves can be used to compare
وهكذا يمكن استخدام منحنيات الإرجاع والدقة لمقارنة
algorithms in addition to understanding one.
الخوارزميات بالإضافة إلى فهمها.
So for example,
إذن، على سبيل المثال،
let's say you have two classifiers, classifier A and classifier B.
لنفترض أن لديك تصنيفين، التصنيف A والتصنيف B.
And you see that for every single point, classifier B is higher than classifier A.
وسترى أن لكل نقطة، يكون التصنيف B أعلى من التصنيف A.
In that case we always prefer classifier B.
وفي هذه الحالة فإننا نفضل دائمًا التصنيف B.
No matter what the threshold is, classifier B always gives you
بغض النظر عن العتبة، فإن التصنيف B يعطيك دائمًا
a better precision for the same recall, better precision for same recall.
دقة أفضل للإرجاع نفسه، دقة أفضل لنفس الإرجاع.
So B is always better.
لذا يكون B أفضل دائمًا.
However, life is not always this simple.
ومع ذلك، فإنه الحياة ليست بهذه البساطة
If there's one thing you should learn about thus far, is that life and
إذا كان هناك شيء واحد ينبغي أن تعرفه حول التعلم الآلي حتى الآن، فهو أن الحياة
practice tends to be a bit messy.
والممارسة تميل إلى أن تصبح فوضوية قليلًا.
And so, often what you observe is not classifier A and B like we saw, but
ولذلك، فغالبًا ما ستلاحظه لن يكون التصنيف A وB كما رأينا، ولكن
it's classifier A and C like we're seeing over here.
التصنيف A وC مثلما نرى هنا.
Where there might be one or more cutoff points, where classifier A does better in
حيث قد يكون هناك واحد أو أكثر نقطة قطع، حيث يكون التصنيف A أفضل
some regions of the precision recal curve where classifier B does better in others.
في بعض المناطق من منحنى الإرجاع والدقة بينما يكون التصنيف B أفضل في مناطق أخرى.
So, for example, or C in this case.
إذن، على سبيل المثال، أو C في هذه الحالة.
So for example, if you're interested in very high precision but okay with lower
إذن، على سبيل المثال، إذا كنت تهتم بدقة عالية جدًا وليس لديك مانع مع انخفاض
recall, then you should pick classifier C, because it does better in that region.
الإرجاع، فعليك أن تختار التصنيف C، لأنه الأفضل في تلك المنطقة.
It's higher up, closer to that flat line.
فهو أعلى، وأقرب إلى الخط المسطح.
But, if you cared about getting high recall,
ولكن، إذا كنت تهتم بالحصول على إرجاع عالٍ،
then you should choose classifier A.
فيجب عليك حينئذٍ أن تختار التصنيف A.
Because in the high recall regime, when you pick tease, they're smaller,
لأنه في نظام الإرجاع العالي، عند اختيار التنشيط، فإنها تكون أصغر،
then classifier A tends to do better.
ثم يميل التصنيف A إلى العمل على نحو أفضل.
So you see, it's curve is higher over here.
لذا كما ترى، المنحنى يكون أعلى هنا.
So that's kind of complexity of dealing with machine learning in the real world.
إذًا هذا هو نوع من التعقيد الذي نواجهه أثناء التعامل مع التعلم الآلي في العالم الحقيقي.
Now if you just had to pick one classifier,
الآن إذا كان عليك فقط اختيار تصنيف واحد،
the question is how do you decide?
فالسؤال هو كيف تقرر؟
How do you choose between A and C in this case?
كيف يمكنك أن تختار بين A وC في هذه الحالة؟
And we often the single number to decide, as I was hinting at,
ونحن كثيرًا ما نقر بعدد واحد، كما كنت ألمح،
depends on where you want to be in the precision trade off curve.
اعتمادًا على أين تريد أن تكون في منحنى مقايضة الدقة.
And there's many metrics out there to try to do single numbers,
وهناك العديد من المقاييس هناك التي تحاول القيام بعدد واحد،
some are called F1 measures, some called area-under-the-curve.
ويسمى بعضها قياسات F1، والبعض الآخر يسمى المساحة تحت المنحنى.
I'm less fond of those measures,
وأنا لا أفضل تلك القياسات عن نفسي،
myself, for a lot of applications than I am of one that's much simpler.
شخصيًا، بالنسبة لكثير من التطبيقات، حيث أفضل القياسات الأكثر بساطة.
Which, it's called precision at k.
والتي يُطلق عليها الدقة في k.
And let me talk about that because it's a really simple measure, really useful.
واسمحوا لي أن أتحدث عن ذلك لأنه مقياس بسيط حقًا، ومفيد حقًا.
So, let's say that there's five slots on my website to show sentences.
إذًا، دعنا نقول إن هناك خمس فتحات في موقعي لإظهار الجمل.
That's all I care about.
هذا هو ما أهتم به فقط.
I want to show five great sentences on my website.
فأنا أريد أن أظهر خمس عبارات إيجابية على موقعي الإلكتروني.
I don't have room for ten million, for five million, just for five.
أنا ليست لدي مساحة لعشرة ملايين، أو لخمسة ملايين، فقط لخمسة.
And I show five sentences there.
وسأظهر خمس عبارات هنا.
Four were great and one sucked.
كانت أربعة رائعة وواحدة كانت سيئة.
I want all five to be great.
أريد لجميع الجمل أن تكون رائعة.
So I want my precision for the five top sentences, for
لذلك أريد دقتي لأفضل خمس جمل،
the top five, to be as good as possible.
أعلى خمسة، أن تكون جيدة بقدر الإمكان.
In this case, our precision was four out of five, 0.8.
وفي هذه الحالة، كانت دقتنا أربعة من أصل خمسة، 0.8.
So I ended up putting a sentence in there that said, my wife tried the ramen and
لذا انتهى بنا الأمر إلى وضع جملة تقول، جربت زوجتي الرامين
it was pretty forgettable.
وكان أقل من العادي.
That's kind of a disappointing thing to put in.
وهذا مخيب للآمال نوعًا ما.
So for many applications, like recommender systems for example, where you
لذا بالنسبة للعديد من التطبيقات، مثل نظم التوصية على سبيل المثال، حيث يمكنك
go to a web page and somebody showing you some products you might want to buy,
تذهب إلى صفحة ويب، ويظهر شخص لك بعض المنتجات التي قد ترغب في شرائها،
precision at k is a really good metric to be thinking about.
الدقة في k هي مقياس جيد حقًا للتفكير فيه.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]